Eric Harrison

Senior Ruby Dev and Software Architect

eric@rubynooby.com

Summary

Eric has been focused on highly scalable web applications written in Ruby for the past 2 years. He is currently responsible for the architecture and design direction of the development team at Classified Adventures. Prior to Classified adventures he worked at realestate.com.au developing and maintaing the website. There he was part of the team that transitioned the platfrom from Perl to Ruby on Rails.

Eric is active in the local Ruby community, giving talks and developing open source gems and plugins. He has experience in meta programming and application architecture.

Coming from a testing and automation background Eric is highly focused on TDD. He has been using XP and Kanban methodologies for 3 years to drive excellent and fast software development.

Eric started he career in web development using PHP. He built applications from the ground up to support the tech support team and management while at 2Wire.

Specialties

Ruby/Rails, TDD, XP, Kanban, MySQL, Perl, meta, open source, LAMP, system administration

Experience

Senior Ruby Developer/Systems Administrator at Classified Ad Ventures

2010 - Present (1 year)

Leads the development team and is responsible for application architecture and design.

Development of web applications using Ruby on Rails, Solr and MySQL. Designed, developed and implemented eMarketing extension to the application framework. Maintained production and UAT systems for applications.

Software Developer at realestate.com.au

May 2009 - March 2010 (11 months)

Maintained codebase and helped with the transition from Perl to Ruby. Was responsible for the transition from legacy ad platform to using DFP from google. Lead to the development of Eric's adify gem which simplifies the building of Ad Tags. Worked on XML property importer in addition to the front end application.

1 recommendation available upon request

Software Developer at REA - Group

2009 - March 2010 (1 year)

QA Developer at realestate.com.au (REA Group)

2007 - May 2009 (2 years)

Designed and developed an automation framework using perl, mechanize and selenium to test web applications. Implemented multiple selenium servers using several browsers and OS. Built and maintained comprehensive test suite.

Software Test Engineer II at Inter-tel

September 2005 - February 2007 (1 year 6 months)

Developed automation test quire written in perl. The system was a proprietary system with a server and client which was written perl. API's and hooks into 3rd party devices where used for testing of Inter-tel's products. Developed a comprehensive test suite for testing hardware.

Systems Engineer at 2Wire

2001 - 2003 (2 years)

Field Engineer at Nortel

2000 - 2001 (1 year)

Tech Support Engineer at Tech Usa

1998 - 2000 (2 years)

Skills

Ruby Ruby on Rails MySQL Meta programming Perl

LAMP

XΡ

TDD

Kanban

Scalability

Server Administration

Software Design

Open Source Software

Software Development

Education

Mesa Community College

Computer Science, 1998 - 1999

Honors and Awards

6 Month Achievement Award (REA Group)

Eric Harrison

Senior Ruby Dev and Software Architect

eric@rubynooby.com



1 person has recommended Eric

"I inherited Eric when he moved over from his role as a QA developer to the development team. Eric always proved himself to be very flexible and eager to learn as well as having a great "can-do" attitude. Eric is very organised and can be left to manage his time and tasks with minimal interference. Eric has a good grounding as a developer and is never afraid to ask for help or advice if needed. I enjoyed working with Eric and would do so again."

— Andy Kelk, Lead Software Developer, realestate.com.au, managed Eric at realestate.com.au

Contact Eric on LinkedIn